printfriendly.com 2019-11-15

# Privacy Policy

At PrintFriendly we don't just treat people how we'd like to be treated... we treat people how we'd like our grandmothers treated. That's right - we're on our best behavior!

If you have questions please contact our [support team](http://support.printfriendly.com/).

We have two products that have different Privacy Policies.

  1. PrintFriendly Pro - A client-side technology used by websites.
  2. PrintFriendly.com - Our website used by individuals and customers of PrintFriendly Pro.

* * *

## PrintFriendly Pro Privacy Policy

#### GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation)

PrintFriendly Pro is GDPR compliant.

PrintFriendly Pro collects personal data when it is necessary to serve the "legitimate interests" of the individual users.

  * No names, address, or other individual information is collected.
  * No IP addresses are collected.
  * No geo information is collected.
  * No web analytic tracking
  * No individual tracking

### Information Collected by PrintFriendly Pro

There are a couple of features of PrintFriendly Pro that can/may require personal data.

#### Email Feature

When an individual emails a PrintFriendly page, email address(es) and optional message are required to generate/send the email ("legitimate interest"). This data is encrypted and sent to the data processor ([SendGrid](https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy/) ) via API to immediately send the email. **Email addresses and message is never saved/stored on PrintFriendly servers**.

#### PDF Feature

If the PDF feature is used, the page content is sent to our server to generate the PDF ("legitimate interest"). We temporarily store the PDF ( up to 60 minutes) so you can access/download the PDF, then the PDF is permanently deleted.

### Cookie Policy for PrintFriendly Pro

 **GDPR and EU ePrivacy Directive Compliant**.[Learn more](http://ec.europa.eu/ipg/basics/legal/cookies/index_en.htm#section_4)

PrintFriendly Pro uses an "essential cookie" to save the individuals preferred font size and PDF page size preference. There is no individual data stored in this cookie. No other cookies are used.

* * *

## PrintFriendly.com Privacy Policy

General Principles:

  * We don’t ask for personal information unless it's needed to provide a service or develop our products.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.

### Information Collected

#### Non Personal Data

PrintFriendly.com collects "log files" like all other websites with non-personally-identifying information such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. PrintFriendly's purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how PrintFriendly's visitors use its services. From time to time, PrintFriendly's may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its service.

#### IP Address:

Internet Protocol (IP) addresses are temporarily gathered to detect and prevent abuse. They are stored for approximately 2 days then permenantly deleted. IP address is also gathered by our data processor (Google) and stored for 30 days.

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include ….

#### Accounts, Purchases and Trials

When you sign up for a trial, create an account, and purchase PrintFriendly Pro your name, email, IP Address, billing details, and optional invoice information is gathered. We use this information to process the payment, generate your invoices, send notices, and provide customer support. The information is encrypted and stored on our servers. To process payment, billing information is encrypted and sent via API to the data processor ([Stripe](https://stripe.com/us/privacy) ).

#### Emailing Customer Support

If you email us, we will keep the content of your message, and your email address so we are able to respond to your request. We do not share or sell this information, nor send unsolicited emails.

#### Emailing A PrintFriendly.com Page

When an individual emails a PrintFriendly.com page, email address(es) and optional message are required to generate/send the email ("legitimate interest").

#### Page Content

If the PDF feature is used, the page content is sent to our server to generate the PDF ("legitimate interest"). We temporarily store the PDF ( up to 60 minutes) so you can access/download the PDF, then the PDF is permanently deleted.

Page content can also be sent to our server to generate a preview on PrintFriendly.com ("legitimate interest"). This content must be publicly accessible on the internet (password protected, secure, or private content is prohibited for use on PrintFriendly.com). Page content is stored for approximately 30 minutes then permanently deleted.

### Cookie Policy

#### Essential Cookies

PrintFriendly Pro uses an "essential cookie" to save the individuals font size and PDF page size preference. There is no individual data stored in this cookie. No other cookies are used.

#### Non-Essential Cookies

We use third party services to provide the following important functions.

  * Web analytics so we can optimize the speed and quality of the service
  * We monetize the free service using ads and partner with trusted ad networks. Publishers can purchase a pro subscription to remove ads ("legitimate interest").

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by PrintFriendly and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on PrintFriendly.com. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to PrintFriendly.com and other sites on the Internet.

### Ad Personalization and Opt Out Information

Google and other third party ad network/exchanges personalize ads to be more relevant. You can opt out of this personalization.

You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at [google.com/ads/preferences/](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/ "Google Dart Cookie Preferences")

Users in the United States may opt out of many third-party ad networks. For example, you may go to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) [Consumer Choice Page](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN "Consumer Choice Page Opt Out Information") for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by [DAA companies](http://www.aboutads.info/participating/ "Interest Based Advertising Companies"). You may also go to the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) [Consumer Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ "NAI Opt Out") for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by [NAI members](http://www.networkadvertising.org/participating-networks "Interest Based Advertising Choices").

Opting out from one or more companies listed on the DAA [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ "DAA Choice Page") or the [NAI Consumer Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ "NAI Consumer Opt Out Page") will opt you out from those companies’ delivery of interest-based content or ads to you, but it does not mean you will no longer receive any advertising through our sites or on other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing (i.e., contextually based ads). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you opt out on the DAA or NAI websites, your opt out may not be effective. Additional information is available on the DAA’s website at [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) or the NAI’s website at [networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

### Protection of Personally-Identifying Information

PrintFriendly discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on PrintFriendly behalf or to provide services available at PrintFriendly's websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using PrintFriendly's websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. PrintFriendly will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, PrintFriendly discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when PrintFriendly believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of PrintFriendly, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of PrintFriendly and have supplied your email address, PrintFriendly may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with PrintFriendly and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. PrintFriendly takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Business Transfers

If PrintFriendly, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that PrintFriendly goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of PrintFriendly may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, PrintFriendly may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in PrintFriendly's sole discretion. PrintFriendly encourages visitors to check this page for changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
